Kyle Tiley Game Designer and Developer kylestiley@gmail.com

Passionate about video games, and the technical and creative disciplines surrounding them. From game design and storytelling to software development and player experience, along with everything in between, I love exploring all aspects of why we are enthralled by video games.

Experience

Fifth Dimension Technologies (5DT)

01/2024 - Present

Software and Simulator Developer

- Developed vehicle entities for mining and construction training simulation software.
- Participated in multiple rounds of quality assurance testing pre-delivery, and client feedback support post-delivery, to ensure the highest quality simulators.
- Designed and co-implemented a new software development training program.

Mental Checkpoint YouTube Channel

09/2022 - 11/2022

Script Writer (Contract)

Commissioned to co-write a YouTube video script relating to game design theory.

Education

Vega School Pretoria

01/2021 - 12/2023

IIE Bachelor of Computer Information Systems in Game Design and Development

Graduated Cum Laude, receiving the Pencil Award for top student in the BCIS Faculty.

Achievements

SA Game Jam 2024

Winner of the Best Hobbyist and Best Narrative categories.

Vega Pretoria Custom Jam 2023

Winner of the Best Overall Game category.

The Campus Game Jam 2022

Winner of the Best Educational Game category.

Skills

• Lua

Programming Languages

Software and Source Control

• C# GDScript • C++ • GLSL • HLSL

 Godot Unity

Aseprite

Linux

Git

SVN